The Possession Experiment is a thriller, horror
film directed by Scott B. Hansen.
When a student takes on a theology project, he taps into
another side that had been hidden away from him.
Brandon Jensen, played by Chris Minor.
Father Mark Campbell, played by Bill Moseley.
Detective Gonzales, played by Eugenia Gonzales.
Brittney, played by Rachel Faulkner.
Jordi, played by Greg Travis.
Michael Scott, played by Mark Joy.
The Philadelphia Experiment was an alleged event claimed to have
been witnessed by an ex-merchant mariner named Carl M.
Allen at the United States Navy's Philadelphia Naval Shipyard in Philadelphia,
Pennsylvania, United States, some time around October 28, 1943.
Allen described an experiment where the U.S.
Navy attempted to make a destroyer escort, USS Eldridge,
disappear and the bizarre results that followed.
The story surfaced in late 1955 when Allen sent a book full of
hand-written annotations referring to the experiment to a U.S.
Navy research organization and, a little later, a series of
letters making further claims to a UFO author.
Allen's account of the event is widely understood to be a hoax.
Several different—and sometimes contradictory—versions of the alleged experiment have
circulated over the years in paranormal literature and popular movies.
Navy maintains that no such experiment was ever conducted, that the details of the story contradict well-established
facts about USS Eldridge, and that the physics the experiment is claimed to be based on are non-existent.
The tone is dark and intense.